ADAM HUMPHREY

2408 Leon Street Apt. 101, Austin, Texas Phone - (512) 663-1160 E-mail - Adamthumph@gmail.com Website - adamhumphrey.github.io GitHub - github.com/AdamHumphrey/

Objective

To find a job where I can use my writing, coding, graphic design and data visualization skills to create compelling content and grow as a journalist.

Summary

I've worked in a variety of newsrooms ranging from a large city newspaper to lifestyle magazines and tech trade magazines. I understand the need to create dynamic content for the web, and work to create content that fits well on phone, tablet and computer screens. I work well under pressure, can think on my feet and strive to meet every deadline.

Experience

Data Visualization and News Apps Intern, Austin American-Statesman Austin, Texas — June 2016 to Present

I create news apps and interactive elements for news stories as well as online projects. I work with data regularly, including writing data-driven stories for different sections of the newspaper.

Digital Intern, Austin Monthly

Austin, Texas - May 2015 to August 2015

My main responsibility was to research and create content for the city magazine's website. I wrote about a wide variety of topics, many times on a strict deadline. I constantly searched for article ideas and maintained other features on the website.

Editorial Intern, NewBay Media

Austin, Texas - January 2015 to August 2015

I copy edited stories and press releases that were sent to be published on the AV Network website. I also wrote several original feature pieces for AV Network's website.

Editorial Intern, The Alcalde

Austin, Texas - August 2014 to December 2014

I researched, pitched, and wrote stories for the bimonthly UT alumni magazine. I also created content for the magazine's website, and proof read material that appeared in the print edition of the magazine.

Education

University of Texas at Austin Bachelor of Journalism — 2012 to 2016

I focused my studies on data journalism, data visualization and coding through my upper division coursework. I took numerous computer science classes in addition to journalism, and practiced my classroom knowledge through my student work at the Daily Texan. After all was said and done I graduated with a 3.61 grade point average.

Skills

- O Data mapping and visualization using ArcGIS, Tableau and Adobe Creative Suite
- Python, Java, HTML5, CSS, and JavaScript coding language experience
- o Create, clean, and manage databases of information
- Strong writer with background writing on a wide variety of topics

Activities

- Phi Kappa Tau Vice President of Operations
- Worked as part of a team which created a iOS app in two months